<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Trackers on danangell.com/blog</title>
    <link>https://danangell.com/blog/tags/trackers/</link>
    <description>danangell.com/blog (Trackers)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 10:25:19 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://danangell.com/blog/tags/trackers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>RIP BaconBits</title>
      <link>https://danangell.com/blog/posts/rip-baconbits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 10:25:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danangell.com/blog/posts/rip-baconbits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After more than 12 years, BaconBits, the unofficial Reddit torrent tracker,
has shut down for good. It&amp;rsquo;s terrible to see such a solid community disappear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On many torrent trackers users are able to request specific content to be
uploaded. As of BaconBits&amp;rsquo; final hours, the request fill ratio stood at 89.28%. A
dedicated community member would provide almost anything you could ask for.
For a site that never had more than 6000 users, that&amp;rsquo;s quite a feat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BaconBits pressed against its user cap of 6000 active accounts for years.
But after a computer error 4 years ago, dubbed the &amp;ldquo;Robot Uprising&amp;rdquo;, the
servers pruned a large portion of tracked torrents. The community and site
never recovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s an excerpt from the original Robot Uprising announcement post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our semi-airgapped database came up with the wrong system time. As in, with a date and time a few years behind&amp;hellip; while the appservers were running on the correct time. That means a bunch of torrents were being marked as last having been seeded &amp;ldquo;a few years ago&amp;rdquo;, while the appservers knew it was 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all fine and dandy except for the fact that we automatically prune torrents that haven&amp;rsquo;t been seeded for &amp;ldquo;2 weeks&amp;rdquo;. From now. The situation unfortunately went unnoticed for a while (12+h).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tl;dr we&amp;rsquo;ve lost about half our uploads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RIP bB. That&amp;rsquo;ll do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://danangell.com/blog/blog/image/bb/bb.gif&#34; alt=&#34;An animated rainbow BaconBits logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
