<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on danangell.com/blog</title>
    <link>https://danangell.com/blog/tags/life/</link>
    <description>danangell.com/blog (Life)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 17:52:32 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://danangell.com/blog/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy Come Easy Go</title>
      <link>https://danangell.com/blog/posts/easy-come-easy-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 17:52:32 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danangell.com/blog/posts/easy-come-easy-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I know what it feels like to make over $1000 per hour. And I&amp;rsquo;m over it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent much of 2020 traveling. As soon as there were rumblings in California of a lockdown, I started looking for ways to preserve my sanity. I had moved to the Bay Area in late 2018 after graduating college. My life was built around the idea that I would have a short commute to Palo Alto from my apartment in Redwood City. Most of my socialization would come through in-person work. My co-workers were great people and some are still close friends today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I knew instinctively that working from home - alone in a studio apartment, in a town where I knew one other person, a place I&amp;rsquo;d moved to 18 months prior - would ruin me. Immediately I started spitballing ideas over Zoom. My proposal to set up pods of people to cowork with got shot down. Thankfully, my close friend and coworker Wenyu was wrapping up his assignment in LA. He&amp;rsquo;d been jump-starting a group of door-to-door salespeople. The pandemic halted our company&amp;rsquo;s legacy operations. A 3 month old unproven initiative involving in-person contact was definitely not in the cards at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On his way up I called him. My lease was now month-to-month, he needed to start a new one, and we both couldn&amp;rsquo;t survive without human contact. We&amp;rsquo;d bonded during a mushroom trip in the Sierra Nevada mountains the previous summer. We decided to go back to the area in a long term AirBnB rental. A third member named Garrett - the only one of us with a car - joined our group. He left his apartment untended in San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We piled into Garrett&amp;rsquo;s old BMW sedan. Two bikes on the back, bags in the trunk, food tucked in every remaining corner. At this point in time little was known about COVID-19. We weren&amp;rsquo;t sure how contagious it was. The CDC was spreading misinformation on masks in an attempt to conserve PPE for medical professionals. I&amp;rsquo;d even ran a cursory calculation for how likely I was to lose a parent to the virus given what information was available. The number was 31%. Of course I knew the statistics I was working from were dubious, but the number still frightened me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived at a cabin in the village of Arnold. This was about as far as you could get into the mountains while still maintaining access to a grocery store. What followed were two of the best months of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cabin&amp;rsquo;s fridge was given a calendar. On it each day had a different chef and meal planned for each lunch and dinner. I was assigned role of head baker. No store-bought bread was allowed! Garrett was master of the vegetables, our preparer of salads (some were very involved). Wenyu was the king of meat - smoked, roasted, fried and broiled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work was slow, so I spent much of my time outside of cooking on my bike. From Arnold it was only 5 miles to Big Trees state park. Big Trees houses a sequoia grove and is worth visiting in an average year. But to have sequoias as a solution to my pandemic boredom was a special privilege. The ride to the park included 600 feet of incline. I had been going to a regular spin class in Palo Alto and was in good enough shape to make the journey. The best part about Big Trees in 2020 was the quasi-closed status. Presumably the state wanted to keep people on payroll, but also wanted to prevent viral exposure. So the park was open only to pedestrians and cyclists. Every time I went, which was often, I was the only person in the park past the gate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One weekend afternoon I took my bike to the logging roads, working from Arnold to Camp Connell before coasting back down route 4. Another weekend I cycled all the way to Lake Alpine. That&amp;rsquo;s 30 miles each way, 4100 feet of incline. Thankfully I didn&amp;rsquo;t get a flat tire because I was too rookie of a cyclist to even think of packing a spare!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember biking past a camp ground about 25 miles into the journey. A lone man stood by the entrance. He watched me pedal up the shoulder of the road. As I passed him he said &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve got the whole world to yourself!&amp;rdquo;. I gave him a chuckle in response. On the way back I coasted down through 30 miles of redwoods. It&amp;rsquo;s an experience I&amp;rsquo;ll never forget. When I got back Wenyu had finished smoking a tri-tip. I ate about 3000 calories of beef, roasted potatoes, and veggies before passing out. In hindsight I had nearly bonked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three of us spent the spring there in Arnold. We watched as snowfall turned to snowmelt. Eventually our lease was up and we all shuffled back to the Bay. But life in the Bay couldn&amp;rsquo;t compare and we soon found ourselves planning for round 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second AirBnB was in Middletown - a little spot one ridge past Napa Valley. This time Garrett was out and Wenyu&amp;rsquo;s cousin Lily was in. Lily is an amazing chef and put us all to shame with her meals. I spent my days lounging on a hammock, my evenings eating meals better than most, and nights in a hot tub. We would frequently look at each other and say &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rsquo;re living our best lives&amp;rdquo;. After two months there we had a couple months in north-eastern Oregon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the hedonic treadmill runs fast and we soon decided to end our travels. I packed my apartment into a storage unit and headed home for the holidays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in Pennsylvania I ended up buying my first car, a Chevy Volt. After New Years I planned to move back to the Bay Area. I took the opportunity to do my first road trip. 3,500 miles across the country. Starting in Philadelphia I visited a friend in Atlanta, dropped by New Orleans to eat the best shrimp of my life, and later found myself in San Antonio visiting a friend named Mike. Mike and I had been friends since High School.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrived in San Antonio late in the day on January 25th, 2021. While he was setting up my makeshift bed on his couch, Mike couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop talking about the GameStop stock. I&amp;rsquo;d been too busy driving the last 3 days to pay much attention to reddit so I had no clue what was going on. As Mike told it the stock price had been going crazy all day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m telling you, it&amp;rsquo;s going to the moon!&amp;rdquo;, he said. Picture in your mind a cartoon of a crazed gold miner. In this moment, Mike matched him in voice and energy. I&amp;rsquo;d just gotten into Robinhood and options trading a few months prior. The idea of gambling on the stock market was new to me, but I at least knew the basics. I&amp;rsquo;d been involved with Bitcoin back in the day and had technically made a profit, but missed on out making some serious wealth. This felt similar to me but with the market closed I put the thought out of mind and went to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning I looked at GameStop&amp;rsquo;s call options. For some reason I trusted Mike. GameStop&amp;rsquo;s value had bounced back from certain death and the market seemed to think this was the peak. It was a Tuesday. I looked at call options for that Friday and bought one contract valued at $1,000. The price was $37 per share and I was betting it&amp;rsquo;d be at least $50 by Friday. Content with my gamble we headed out to look at the Alamo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point Elon Musk tweeted about the GameStop price rise. This caused an explosion in value. Mike noticed this and let me know. I was alread up by thousands of dollars. I doubled down on my bet, buying a new call contract for $10,000. As we sat on the San Antonio river walk drinking beers I watched as my portfolio went up in real time. Over the course of a couple of beers I&amp;rsquo;d made at least $1000. I was giddy. Mike was in a curious mix of happiness from being right and jealousy from the RoI on my options contracts. By night time my $11,000 had turned into over $100,000. I set out the next morning headed West to El Paso.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Friday I sold the contracts. I called Mike. He was convinced the shares were going to $1,000,000. I looked at my 6 figure returns and thought &amp;ldquo;Well, he hasn&amp;rsquo;t steered me wrong yet!&amp;rdquo; and bought back in. A few $100,000 call option contracts later and I was buckled up for the ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some time between El Paso and El Centro, California I checked my portfolio. The highest value I saw was $360,000. I remember calling a different friend to let them know I was about to be outrageously wealthy. But by some time on Monday I woke up to a notification from RobinHood. &amp;ldquo;Your stop loss order has executed&amp;rdquo;. I checked the account and found around $10,000 inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d made a contingency plan. You can tell your broker to automatically sell an asset if the price goes below a certain point. I set it so I would get back my initial investment. Honestly, I don&amp;rsquo;t recall being more than mildly bummed. I&amp;rsquo;d gotten out what I put in and had fun in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can now say I know what it feel like to make over $1,000 per hour. It&amp;rsquo;s good! But that old hedonic treadmill is a bitch. It&amp;rsquo;s been about 4 years since those days and they don&amp;rsquo;t stick out nearly as well as my bike trips in the Sierra Nevadas or the meals with friends tucked into a cabin. Those experiences still come from a place of wealth and privilege, but the $80 per hour kind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that is to say, when someone rips off their employees so they can earn just a little more money for themself they don&amp;rsquo;t know where they are on the treadmill. They&amp;rsquo;ve passed peak happiness long ago.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Skipped to the Ending</title>
      <link>https://danangell.com/blog/posts/i-skipped-to-the-ending/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 10:44:53 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danangell.com/blog/posts/i-skipped-to-the-ending/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was 8 years old I started making websites with my friend. His grandmother had purchased him a domain name and web hosting. It was 2003 and the world was whispering of Web 2.0. Books I checked out of the library talked about DHTML (dynamic HTML, basically what any web app is today). There was no mobile app market, native application development had a high barrier to entry, and the most exciting things happening with computers were websites like eBay and Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together my friend and I would make silly web pages. Basic things like choose-your-own-adventures were fun and easy to make. All you needed were some links to the next pages and you&amp;rsquo;ve made a game! We of course had the most offensive color schemes imaginable. We had 24-bit JPEG backgrounds of landscapes and tropical coasts. They were the most beautiful images I could find online, so why &lt;em&gt;shouldn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; they be the backing for my red 12pt Times New Roman text?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point I saw a picture in the Philadelphia Inquirer of a slide in an office building and an all-you-can-eat &lt;em&gt;free&lt;/em&gt; candy dispenser. Google was becoming the first &amp;ldquo;web scale&amp;rdquo; company in real time. And they were rewarding the employees handsomely for reshaping the world. Every year they would release a reality-altering product. Google Earth blew my mind. I could spend hours scanning around in the American deserts finding interesting canyons and mountains. In high school I had my own personal site that functioned mostly as a blog. It was a major point of pride that I wrote the HTML and CSS by hand - I even made the graphics myself in Paint. At least one post showcased the highlights of my discoveries in the satellite imagery of Google Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My family would all talk about how some day I&amp;rsquo;d work for Google. I believed them and considered Google to be the apex of a programmer&amp;rsquo;s career. They paid the most, got the most done, and their employees held the most respect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when I graduated with my Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s in CS and got a cold email from a recruiter I was ecstatic! Soon they flew me off to interview on-site in Seattle. I can only guess why, but I did not make the cut. My fall-back was to go work in startups in Silicon Valley. I already had a few good projects, co-ops, and part time jobs under my belt. My experience earned me a few competing job offers. I picked the better of the two and moved across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What shocked me was how healthy the startup job was. There was no grinding, a good work-life balance, and a set of 20 kind and knowledgeable co-workers. Everyone was there because they &lt;em&gt;wanted&lt;/em&gt; to be there. We all wanted to build something, together. I sat next to the founding engineer for a year and learned more per day than I ever had before or have since. The guy was notoriously blunt. His bluntness honed my edge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the pandemic I switched jobs to work at a rapidly growing startup in the emerging AI/LLM space. I had dropped into a runaway success. After only 8 months the founders had achieved thousands of signups per day, millions in ARR, and I was here to rewrite everything from scratch. We shipped the rewrite after a couple of months and used the fire hose of new users to iterate on on-boarding and product functionality. Being able to go from ticket to PR, LGTM, release, and get metrics in a hour is an amazing way to learn. Consistent, fast feedback is one of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5eW6Eagr9XA&#34;&gt;key aspects&lt;/a&gt; to becoming an expert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But for all of the team&amp;rsquo;s virtues we also had our failings. Soon it became clear that we didn&amp;rsquo;t have a strong direction in the face of a rapidly changing landscape. A GPT-3 app could not stand still, certainly not one with VC funding. I started to grow uncertain of the value of my time spent there. Then I got another cold email from Google. They wanted me to interview again. I gave it a shot and got an offer for an L4 SWE position. After almost 20 years I had gotten into the magic place with slides and free candy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figuring I might as well take the opportunity to try some different work, I joined a team working on phone firmware. After a couple of weeks the tech lead quit. My manager would often not reply to my emails. They told me I didn&amp;rsquo;t need to do any work for the first couple of months. This is the last thing I wanted to hear. When I did get work assigned I was immediately thrown into the jaws of bureaucracy. A project to help us track errors in production would take months. Most of that time got allocated to getting Privacy Council approval because we would be logging strings. My team all lived nearby but rarely came in to the office. Virtual meetings were held with cameras off. Co-workers started quitting left and right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came to realize that I had joined the wrong version of the team. There was one team working on this product specifically for first-party phones, and another for the platform at large. But because Google refused to offer support to 3rd party OEMs, even at a price, none would sign on. Hiring got frozen so I couldn&amp;rsquo;t switch to the &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so my new skip manager told me he would have the team shut down and I switched to an adjacent team managing a certificate authority. This would be web-based work. After my failed entry into Rust firmware development I was glad to go back to my roots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it turned out, the web side of this project was maintained by another department. I was on loan to them. I got assigned a &amp;ldquo;dotted-line manager&amp;rdquo;. When I first met him he gave me a speech about how he didn&amp;rsquo;t want to hear anything about my working on 20% projects - &amp;ldquo;they always end up being more than 20%&amp;rdquo;. He didn&amp;rsquo;t want me to get pulled into work by my direct manager. He felt he owned me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After finishing my first project I made the mistake of picking up new work because I had nothing else to do. Mr. Dotted-Line and his team had put together a list of tasks for the next few quarters without me. I picked the first unassigned item in the document and sent out a design document for what would end up being 200-300 lines of code. Big mistake - I was going rogue. Dotted-Line contacted my skip manager demanding I be reined in. My skip and direct managers had my back, but I still felt awful. Was I not supposed to be learning? Building?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that my other managers were amazing to be around. My direct manager would fantasize about monetizing male loneliness through futuristic sex robots. Later, when my skip manager was staging a coup to steal Dotted-Line&amp;rsquo;s project he pulled the other guy into a call. During the call he opened up a group chat with my team, writing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skip&lt;/strong&gt;: He is fighting it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skip&lt;/strong&gt;: But he also looks like his dog got shot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skip&lt;/strong&gt;: He is now pitching for us to work better together&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skip&lt;/strong&gt;: Feels like a breakup lol&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;no one responded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Those guys over there are so toxic&amp;rdquo; was a favorite phrase for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I realized this project was no better than the last one I made my complaints clear to my direct manager. I told him my issues were with the company itself and had no optimism that working on yet another project would fix things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He told me (paraphrasing) &amp;ldquo;Well, you know it&amp;rsquo;s really a lot of paper-work to fire you. You could just get away with doing nothing for 12 months.&amp;rdquo; Again, not what I wanted to hear. Why tell me this? Presumably for him this was a way to pad his head-count. One of the primary metrics for leadership success at Google is how many people you have under you. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if one, two, or more aren&amp;rsquo;t working - as long as you are meeting your self-defined OKRs you&amp;rsquo;ll look good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the same motivator for why my dotted-line manager wanted to steal me. Hiring got frozen - the only way to get that sweet sweet head-count is to take it from someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after 15 months I was out of there. I learned that I don&amp;rsquo;t care about the money Google pays. I don&amp;rsquo;t care about the high scale of influence your work can have. I skipped from series A startup to mature IPO&amp;rsquo;d company and cheated myself out of the experiences you get in-between. I want to &lt;em&gt;earn&lt;/em&gt; the scale through hard work. For me FAANG was not a place to learn, it was a way to get paid. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t come to Silicon Valley to get paid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;
    &lt;i&gt;
        P.S: I want to be clear that all of the ICs I worked with were great. If any of them read this they should know I appreciated their time spent working with me.
    &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/sup&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
